<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/">
    <channel>
        <title>Blog - Belgian Police Internet Platform</title>
        <description>A product blog about developing and iterating the Belgian Police Internet Platform. For the people who publish content to their site and anyone else who is interested.</description>
        <link>http://www.openpolice.be</link>
        <atom:link href="http://www.openpolice.be/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Status update</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2014/06/27/status-update.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2014/06/27/status-update.html</guid>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                
                    <img width="800" src="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-03-21/news.jpg" alt="" />
                
                <p>Since our <a href="http://belgianpolice.github.io/blog/2014/03/21/status-update.html">previous status update</a>, just over 3 months ago,
we have closed down 2 releases (<a href="https://github.com/belgianpolice/internet-platform/releases/tag/v2.4">v2.4</a> &amp; <a href="https://github.com/belgianpolice/internet-platform/releases/tag/v2.5">v2.5</a>) resulting in more then 80 closed development tickets.
These releases include a mix of bug fixes and new features.</p>

<p>A few of the most important changes:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Added Press<sup>*</sup> component, see <a href="http://www.lokalepolitie.be/5888/pers">Politie MidLim</a></li>
  <li>Added BIN/RIQ<sup>*</sup> component, <a href="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-06-27/bin.png" data-gallery="enabled">see screenshot</a></li>
  <li>Added ‘note’ field and ‘appointment only’ to office hours in Contacts, <a href="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-06-27/office-hours.png" data-gallery="enabled">see screenshot</a></li>
</ul>

<p><sup>*</sup> Optional - create a support ticket to enable it for your site.</p>

<h2 id="rollout">Rollout</h2>
<p>Over the past three months we have also organised two training sessions (April &amp; June) resulting in 50 police zones who have access to the new platform. Two of those, <a href="http://www.lokalepolitie.be/5888">Politie MidLim</a> and <a href="http://www.policelocale.be/5317">Police Mouscron</a> have released their new website a few weeks ago.</p>

<p>We are very happy that 9 months after the initial release of the new platform 25% of all police zones have received training and started migrating their website to the new platform.</p>

<p>Planning for the next training sessions in September and November has already started.
Create a support ticket or <a href="&#109;&#097;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;:&#098;&#101;&#108;&#103;&#105;&#097;&#110;&#112;&#111;&#108;&#105;&#099;&#101;&#064;&#103;&#109;&#097;&#105;&#108;&#046;&#099;&#111;&#109;">drop us an email</a> if you want to join one of the upcoming training sessions.</p>

                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The rise of mobile</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2014/05/31/the-rise-of-mobile.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2014/05/31/the-rise-of-mobile.html</guid>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                
                    <img width="800" src="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-03-21/district-search.jpg" alt="" />
                
                <p>The objective of the Belgian Police Internet Platform is to provide all new and prospective information in the format that is right for our users, whatever their device. The new platform that is currently in rollout is the beginning of this process as we aim to improve our digital services.</p>

<p>Here’s a graph showing how the devices people use to visit the website of their Police zone have changed. To be precise, the data is for visits collected across the 110 Police zones, Belgium counts 194 police zones, who are using v1 or v2 of the Belgian Police Internet Platform.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/percentages-of-visits-from-desktop-mobile-and-tablet.jpg" alt="Percentages of visits from desktop mobile and tablet" /></p>

<p>In the first quarter of 2014, 75% of visits have come from a desktop computer, 15% from a mobile and 10% from a tablet. In the first quarter of 2012 it was 95% desktop computer, 3% mobile and 2% tablet.</p>

<p>Shifts in the devices people use to access the internet should come as no surprise, but the pace of change might. And I do not expect this switch away from desktop computers towards more personal, portable, touchscreen devices to slow down anytime soon.</p>

<h2 id="mobile-first">Mobile First</h2>
<p>Designing for small screens can be a real challenge. Which is why we have rebuilt the template from the ground up and rethought the information architecture using a “Mobile First” approach.</p>

<p>Why? Simply, it’s often easier to make a website also work for a desktop monitor and keyboard if you’ve already made it work really well on a small touchscreen than it is to go the other way.</p>

                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Global Accessibility Awareness Day</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2014/05/15/global-accessibility-awareness-day.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2014/05/15/global-accessibility-awareness-day.html</guid>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                
                    <img width="800" src="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/accessibility.jpg" alt="" />
                
                <p>Today is the <a href="http://globalaccessibilityawarenessday.org/">Global Accessibility Awareness Day</a>, a community-driven effort whose goal is to dedicate one day to raising the profile of and introducing the topic of digital accessibility and people with different disabilities to the broadest audience possible.</p>

<p>The target audience of Global Accessibility Awareness Day is the design, development, usability, and related communities who build, shape, fund and influence technology and its use. While people may be interested in the topic of making technology accessible and usable by persons with disabilities, the reality is that they often do not know how or where to start. Awareness comes first.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-accessibility">What is Accessibility</h2>
<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accessibility">Accessibility</a> is the degree to which a product, device, service, or environment is available to as many people as possible. Accessibility can be viewed as the “ability to access” and benefit from some system or entity. The concept often focuses on people with disabilities or special needs and their right of access, enabling the use of assistive technology.</p>

<h2 id="content-is-king">Content is king</h2>
<p>An important part of creating an accessible website is writing accessible content.</p>

<h3 id="use-headings">Use headings</h3>
<p>Use the heading styles to create a logical document structure.</p>

<h3 id="use-lists">Use lists</h3>
<p>Use the list styles to group together related items. If the items follow a specific sequence, use a numbered list instead. Don’t use punctuation or other markers to create the illusion of a list.</p>

<h3 id="use-readable-body-text">Use readable body text</h3>
<p>Use left aligned text (unless the language of your document is read right to left). Don’t use justified text in your document.</p>

<p>Don’t use chunks of italicised or capitalised text, and don’t underline text unless it’s a link.</p>

<h3 id="use-data-tables">Use data tables</h3>
<p>Use tables with column headings to display data. Don’t use tables to make cosmetic changes to the layout of the document.</p>

                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Status update</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2014/03/21/status-update.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2014/03/21/status-update.html</guid>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                
                    <img width="800" src="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-03-21/medium-screens.jpg" alt="" />
                
                <p>Since the initial release of <a href="http://www.lokalepolitie.be/5388">Politie Leuven</a> last September we have closed down 3 releases (<a href="https://github.com/belgianpolice/internet-platform/releases/tag/v2.1">v2.1</a>, <a href="https://github.com/belgianpolice/internet-platform/releases/tag/v2.2">v2.2</a> &amp; <a href="https://github.com/belgianpolice/internet-platform/releases/tag/v2.3">v2.3</a>), resulting in more then 100 closed development tickets. These releases include a mix of bug fixes and improvements (look &amp; feel, speed performance, accessibility, …).</p>

<!--more-->

<p>A few of the most important changes:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Hamburger icon on small screens is replaced with an (animated) button, <a href="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-03-21/menu-button.jpg" data-gallery="enabled">see screenshot</a></li>
  <li>On medium screens the menu is fully visible, <a href="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-03-21/medium-screens.jpg" data-gallery="enabled">see screenshot</a></li>
  <li>News on the homepage groups 3 articles (one with introtext), <a href="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-03-21/news.jpg" data-gallery="enabled">see screenshot</a></li>
  <li>Office hours are added as structured data instead of plain text, <a href="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-03-21/office-hours.jpg" data-gallery="enabled">see screenshot</a></li>
  <li>News articles support <a href="https://dev.twitter.com/docs/cards/types/summary-card">Twitter Summary Card</a>, <a href="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-03-21/twitter-card.jpg" data-gallery="enabled">see screenshot</a></li>
  <li>District officer search form now includes the house number, <a href="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2014/2014-03-21/district-search.jpg" data-gallery="enabled">see screenshot</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="rollout">Rollout</h2>

<p>All pilot zones have received dedicated training and access to their new website, including the zones who are part of our development community. One of those, <a href="http://www.lokalepolitie.be/5446">Politie Damme/Knokke-Heist</a> has released their website a few weeks ago.</p>

<p>Our next step (phase 2) will be targeted towards all the zones who are a member of the VCLP-CPPL. In just two weeks we will host a training session for these webmasters.</p>

<p>We are aiming to start phase 3 in June for the next group of 20 zones. If everything keeps running smoothly we will organise a training for 20 zones every 10 weeks.</p>

<p>Because the new platform features a complete new information architecture an overnight migration of your existing website is not possible. The new information architecture requires a complete re-development of each site content, adding streets, FAQ’s, local police officers, contact information and reworking the existing content.</p>

<p>We will therefor kindly ask all participating zones to make the necessary resources available to complete the migration in 10 weeks so we can start with another group.</p>

                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Second website released</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2013/10/26/second-website-released.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2013/10/26/second-website-released.html</guid>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                
                    <img width="800" src="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2013/warneton.jpg" alt="" />
                
                <p>We are happy to inform you that we released the second website on the new platform last week, <a href="http://www.lokalepolitie.be/5318">Police Comines-Warneton</a>.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>Since the initial release of the Belgian Police Internet Platform, with the website of <a href="http://www.lokalepolitie.be/5388">Politie Leuven</a>, six weeks ago we have closed down more then 20 development tickets resulting in our first maintenance release (v2.1).</p>

<p>This release include a mix of bug fixes and improvements, check the <a href="https://github.com/belgianpolice/internet-platform/releases/tag/v2.1">release notes</a> for more information.</p>

<p>The new web platform is a major step towards providing easy to find information whatever device (desktop/tablet/mobile) a visitor is using. Featuring easy access to: district officers, contact information, frequently asked questions, traffic information.</p>

                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Belgian Police Internet Platform released</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2013/09/15/belgian-police-internet-platform-released.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.openpolice.be/blog/2013/09/15/belgian-police-internet-platform-released.html</guid>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                
                    <img width="800" src="http://www.openpolice.be/images/blog/2013/release.jpg" alt="" />
                
                <p>We are very happy to inform you that one year after the demo of the new internet platform the first website, <a href="http://www.lokalepolitie.be/5388">Politie Leuven</a>, has been released a few days ago.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>Over the past year we have heavily improved the platform. Most importantly, we have rebuilt the template from the ground up and rethought the information architecture using a “Mobile First” approach.</p>

<p>Aim of the new template is to provide the best user experience for citizens, whatever their device. The new web platform is a major step towards providing easy to find information. Featuring easy access to: district officers, contact information, frequently asked questions, traffic information.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“With the increase in popularity of mobile devices, it is important to provide all new and prospective information in the format that is right for the citizen, whatever their device. The new platform is the beginning of this process as we aim to improve our services online.” - Marc Alen, Coach ICT (VCLP/CPPL)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>We are thrilled with the positive feedback we received in the past days. Because the new platform features a complete new information architecture an overnight migration of your existing website is not possible.</p>

<p>The new information architecture requires a complete re-development of each site content, adding streets, FAQ’s, local police officers, contact information and reworking the existing content. Sites cannot be migrated automatically.</p>

<p>Initially we’d start rolling-out new sites zone by zone, working closely with each zone and then evaluate how we go from there. The next site will be Police de Comines-Warneton, also the first french site. Simultaneous we are working on stabilising the new platform, and of course maintaining the current platform.</p>

                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>